Guide to the Records of the American Institute of the City of New York for the Encouragement of Science and Invention 1808-1983 (bulk, 1828-1940) MS 17
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Annual Fair Years, 1808-1930
  - Subseries 1: Annual Fairs, 1828-1926
    - Entry Blanks - 65th Fair of the American Institute, 1896 (3 of 5) (Offsite-box 69, Folder 2)
    - Entry Blanks - 65th Fair of the American Institute, 1896 (4 of 5) (Offsite-box 69, Folder 3)
    - Entry Blanks - 65th Fair of the American Institute, 1896 (5 of 5) (Offsite-box 69, Folder 4)
    - Entries - Dept III Group 1; Dept IV Group 1; Dept V Group 1 [1896] (Removed from Bound Volume: "Receipts for Entry Fees, 65th Annual Fair of the American Institute") (Offsite-box 69, Folder 5)
    - "Judges Report 65th Fair 1896" - 1 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 6)
    - Judges' Report 65th Fair - 2, 1896 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 7)
    - Judges' Report 65th Fair 1896 - 3 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 8)
    - Judges' Report 65th Fair 1896 - 4 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 9)
    - Judges' Report 65th Fair 1896 - 5 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 1)
    - Judges' Report 65th Fair 1896 - 6 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 2)
    - Judges' Report 65th Fair 1896 - 7 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 3)
    - Judges' Lists - 65th Annual Fair of the American Institute, 1896 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 4)
    - Judges' Lists, n. d., [1896] (Offsite-box 70, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - 65th Fair, 1896-1897 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 6)
    - "Vouchers 65th Fair 1896", 1896 (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 70, Folder 7)
    - "Vouchers 65th Fair 1896", 1896 (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 70, Folder 8)
    - Vouchers 65th Fair 1896 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 9)
    - Entry Blanks - 66th American Institute Fair, 1897 (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 70, Folder 10)
    - Entry Blanks - 66th American Institute Fair, 1897 (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 70, Folder 11)
    - Entry Blanks - 66th Annual Fair, 1897 (1 of 6) (Offsite-box 71, Folder 1)
    - Entry Blanks - Exhibitors' Descriptions to Judges, 66th Annual Fair [Applications for Space], 1897 (2 of 6) (Offsite-box 71, Folder 2)
    - Entry Blanks - Exhibitors' Descriptions to Judges, 66th Annual Fair [Applications for Space], 1897 (3 of 6) (Offsite-box 71, Folder 3)
    - Entry Blanks - Exhibitors' Descriptions to Judges, 66th Annual Fair [Applications for Space], 1897 (4 of 6) (Offsite-box 71, Folder 4)
    - Entry Blanks - Exhibitors' Descriptions to Judges, 66th Annual Fair [Applications for Space], 1897 (5 of 6) (Offsite-box 71, Folder 5)
    - Entry Blanks - 66th Fair Exhibitors' Descriptions to Judges [Applications for Space], 1897 (6 of 6) (Offsite-box 71, Folder 6)
    - "Judges Reports 66th Fair 1897", 1897 (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 1)
    - "Judges Reports 66th Fair 1897", 1897 (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 2)
    - "Voucher 66th Fair 1897", 1897 (1 of 3) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 3)
    - "Vouchers 66th Fair 1897", 1897 (2 of 3) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 4)
    - "Vouchers 66th Fair 1897", 1897 (3 of 3) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 5)
    - "Bills, 67th Exhibition of the American Institute at National Academy of Design - Sept. 26 to Oct. 8th 1898", 1898 (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 6)
    - "Bills, 67th Exhibition of the American Institute at National Academy of Design - Sept. 26 to Oct. 8th 1898", 1898 (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 72, Folder 7)
    - List of Premiums Awarded and Announcements of Annual Fairs Including Flower Shows, 1900-1903, 1905, 1908, 1913-1920, 1922, 1924 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 1)
    - Duplicate Vouchers of Prizes Awarded - 81st Fair of the American Institute, 1909-1912 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 2)
    - "Chrysanthemum Show - November 9th to 11th 1910, Entries, Letters, etc." (Offsite-box 73, Folder 3)
    - "Dahlia Show Sept. 20 to 22nd 1910, Entries, Letters, etc." (Offsite-box 73, Folder 4)
    - "Chrysanthemum Show, Nov. 1st to 3rd, 1911, Entries, Letters, etc." (Offsite-box 73, Folder 5)
    - "Dahlia Show - Sept. 19th to 21st 1911, Entries, Letters, etc." (Offsite-box 73, Folder 6)
    - " - 1911 - Contains - Correspondence - Reports - President - Ticket Committee - Finance Committee - Nominating Committee - 7th Dept. Premiums" (Offsite-box 73, Folder 7)
    - "Chrysanthemum [Show] - November 6th [1912] - Entries, Letters, etc." (Offsite-box 73, Folder 8)
    - "Dahlia Show - Sept 24th to 26th 1912, Entries, Letters, etc." (Offsite-box 73, Folder 9)
    - Lists of Premiums Awarded, 1922, 1924 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 14)
    - The American Institute's Inventors Exposition, 1925 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 15)
    - 94th Annual Fair, Exposition of Inventions, 1925 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 16)
    - Contract for Space at the 95th Annual Fair, 1926 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2: Administrative, 1808-1930
    The most common types of material in the Administrative subseries are correspondence, reports, accounts, and business and financial papers.
    Specific types of material include:
    Correspondence - Much of the correspondence has to do with the day-to day business of the Institute, and deals with matters such as proposed members, invited speakers or lecturers, and exchanges of courtesies with other organizations, such as the Franklin Institute in Philadelphia. Other letters acknowledge honorary memberships, or other courtesies conferred on prominent persons. Former New York Governor Morgan Lewis sends his thanks to the Institute for granting him an Honorary Membership in 1839, as does Governor Charles Evans Hughes in 1908. Lord Lyons, the British Minister to the United States, expresses his appreciation for a multi-volume set of the Transactions of the American Institute sent to him in 1859.
    Another major subject of the correspondence concerns the American Institute's annual fairs. Firms and individuals inquired about exhibiting their products or inventions. Some exhibitors sent letters expressing their dissatisfaction at having been passed over for the top prizes. Winners of prizes awarded by the Institute at its Annual Fairs often sent letters of thanks, but on some occasions needed more specific attention. For example, Samuel Colt inquired in 1850 if the Institute would replace medals that had been lost or stolen.
    In addition to correspondence from exhibitors and prize-winners, correspondence pertaining to the organization of the fairs appears in the collection. This material concerns such matters as bids for concession stands, space allocation, exhibition venues, the striking of medals to be awarded, and invitations to speakers and guests. Material dated 1859 concerns the fire that destroyed the New York Crystal Palace, an Institute-owned property that served as the venue for its fairs in the late 1850's.
    Some of the early correspondence, however, addresses non-administrative matters of interest to the Institute. J. R. Barbour of Massachusetts was one of many correspondents who periodically wrote to the Institute about silk manufacturing. In a series of letters dated 1837, publisher and economist Matthew Carey writes about his publication of a new edition of The Wealth of Nations, and comments on the financial panic of that year. An 1842 letter from U.S. Treasury Secretary Walter Forward answers an Institute inquiry regarding regulations for vessels trading between U.S. and Canadian ports on the Great Lakes. Other letters are from inventors, and concern matters such as technological advances and patent law. An 1836 letter from Charles Goodyear, for example, details the inventor's experiments with rubber.
    Business and financial affairs began to figure prominently in the Institute's correspondence in the years after the Civil War. In addition to administrative material dealing with such matters as membership and Institute-sponsored events, papers detailing the Institute's real estate and bond holdings appear in the collection. This material includes leases, contracts, mortgages, insurance policies, and correspondence. Specific subjects include the Institute's plans to purchase the Empire Skating Rink in 1871, and the effects of a proposed subway route on an Institute-owned property at 351 Broadway in 1913.
    Reports - Much of the material from the years 1828 to 1928 consists of four types of reports. First, there are reports of the standing committees of the Institute, such as the Finance Committee, Library Committee, and Committee on Membership. Bound volumes of reports of standing committees generally contain transcripts of reports found among the material in folders. Second, there are reports of Committees comprised of persons appointed by the Institute to evaluate new technological processes, machinery, and scientific literature, as well as as legislation. Third, there are reports from the various sections within the American Institute, such as the Farmers' Club, the Photographical Section, and the Polytechnic Section. Fourth, there are reports of committees appointed to examine specific internal affairs of the American Institute.
    Standing committees of the American Institute included Finance, Membership, Lectures, Library, Annual Fairs, Elections, Arts and Sciences, Commerce, Agriculture, and Constitution and By-Lawsand their reports reflect committee activity. The reports of the Committee on Elections, for example, include the names of those members nominated for offices in the Institute, and the tallies of votes for each. The Membership Committee recorded the names of proposed members, and the names of the members who sponsored them. Standing Committee reports were submitted annually during the 19th Century. Beginning in the early in 1901, Finance Committee reports were submitted quarterly.
    The four standing committees with the most varied tasks were Committee on Manufactures, Arts and Sciences, the Committee on Commerce, and the Committee on Agriculture. In addition to specific reports that the Institute commissioned to evaluate new inventions, the Committee on Manufactures, Arts and Sciences also reported on technological developments. The subjects of the reports include improved railway cars (1842), an airtight coal stove (1846), and a portable steam saw (1857). The Committee on Agriculture reported on cultivation and stock rearing, primarily in the Northeast. Members of the Farmers' Club of the American Institute periodically reported to the Committee on crops and livestock. The Committee on Commerce examined questions such as the relative merits of steam and sailing vessels.
    Proposals for new inventions, or new applications for existing ones, were often submitted to the Institute by persons who sought the Institute's support or approval. These proposals were turned over to experts who assessed their utility. Most of these reports are from committees of such authorities, but some reports were submitted by individuals. In an 1846 report, John James Audubon gave his opinion of an ornithology text that the Institute had asked him to critique. In 1850, a committee that included Samuel F.B. Morse evaluated an improvement to telegraphic apparatus. Other reports assessed the feasibility of an elevated railway in New York City (1848), and evaluated an early steam-powered automobile (1856). Committees also returned reports on particular subjects not directly related to specific inventions, but to technological matters in general. Subjects of such reports include the causes and prevention of explosions of steam boilers (1834), a tour of the Singer Sewing Machine plant (1865), and the use of rock salt on roads in the 1860s and its ill effect on horses.
    After the Civil War, committee reports on new technologies become less frequent. During this period, the Institute's Polytechnic Section received papers and organized lecture series regarding various inventions and technologies. In some cases, these papers are appended to the reports that the section submitted detailing the proceedings of its meetings. Subjects of these lectures and papers included: underground placement of telegraph wires, raising sunken ships by using air bags, Edison's experiments with electromagnetism, and climatology.
    Other reports dealt with the workings of the Institute itself. In 1840, some of the officers of the American Institute were accused of malfeasance. The Institute appointed a committee to investigate the allegations, and in addition to a report on the incident, the collection details of the charges brought against the accused, statements of the accused, and the testimony and affidavits of witnesses. An 1860 internal report details the "Rise and Progress of the American Institute." A report from 1892 recommends that the Institute's Annual Fairs be discontinued, and makes proposals for the future course the Institute generally.
    Business and Financial Records - Bound volumes include Treasurer's Accounts, journals, ledgers, cash books, check books, receipt books, and records of members' admission fees and dues. Material in folders includes insurance policies, leases, contracts, bills, receipts, and invoices and "petty cash" vouchers. The bills and receipts include those for rent for the offices of the American Institute, gas and light, magazine and newspaper subscriptions, office furniture, and honoraria for speakers and lecturers.
    Minutes - Minutes include trustees minutes and committee minutes. Most of this material is in folders. Most of the minute books contain abstracts of minutes, rather than the minutes themselves.
    Membership information - Applications and proposals for membership are included in the foldered material. Among the bound volumes are alphabetical lists of annual members for the years 1831 to 1919 (bulk dates are 1841 to 1897). There is also an undated group of volumes listing the names of Life Members.
    Library records - Included are reports of the Library Committee which detail the budget, use, and acquisitions of the Institute's Library. Bound volumesinclude library catalogues, a visitor's register, and a circulation book.
    Researchers consulting administrative information are encouraged to also consult any pertinent bound volumes (Subseries 3) for the corresponding time period.
    - "A List of Treaties between Great Britain and Other Powers from the Year 1788 to 1808" (Offsite-box 75, Folder 1)
    - "Reports and Papers, 1827 to 1838" (1 of 2), 1827-1833 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 2)
    - "Reports and Papers, 1827 to 1838" (2 of 2), 1834-1838 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 3)
    - Reports and Papers, 1828 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 4)
    - "Bills Paid", 1828-1832 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 5)
    - "Treasurers Accounts - 1. John H. Lidell, 3. George Bacons, 2. Joseph Titcomb", 1831-1838 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 6)
    - Receipts, 1833 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 7)
    - "Letters 1834", 1833-1834 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 8)
    - "Explosion of Steam Boilers, Prof. Renwick's lecture, Aikin's railway sale of No. 41 Cortland St. Order of Chancellor", 1834 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 9)
    - Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1834-1835 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 10)
    - "Collections by Alonzo Wakeman, 1835'6, 1836'7, 1837'8, 1838'9", 1834-1839 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 11)
    - Report of Finance Committee 1835 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 12)
    - "Letters - 1835", 1835-1836 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 13)
    - "Accounts of T.B. Wakeman 1836, 1837,1838 and Vouchers, Old books of collections 1831" (Offsite-box 75, Folder 14)
    - "Letters - 1836" (1 of 3) (Offsite-box 75, Folder 15)
    - "Letters - 1836" (2 of 3) (Offsite-box 75, Folder 16)
    - "Letters - 1836" (3 of 3), 1836-1837 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 1)
    - "Payments by Alonzo Wakeman from June 1836 to March 1839", 1836-1839 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 2)
    - "Letters - 1837", 1836-1837 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 3)
    - "Amusing Bits - 1837", 1836-1837 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 4)
    - Cancelled Checks, 1838-1840 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 5)
    - "T.B. Wakeman's Accounts viz. Rent, Salary, Library, Expense and General Acct. - Jan. 1838", 1833-1838 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 6)
    - "Financial Receipts and Expenditures of the American Institute 1841 to 1847; 11, 12, 13 Fairs; 1838 to 1840 and Other Reports", 1838-1847 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 7)
    - Applications for Membership - 1839 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 8)
    - Letters, 1839 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 9)
    - "Letters - 1839, Reports and Papers - 1839", 1837-1840 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 10)
    - "Resignations as Members of the American Institute", 1839-1842 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 11)
    - "Vouchers from April 1839 to April 1840", 1839-1840 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 12)
    - Reports and Papers, N. D. [ca. 1830s] (Offsite-box 76, Folder 13)
    - Accounts 1840 - 1844 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 14)
    - "Applications for Membership - 1840", 1839-1840 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 1)
    - "Investigation of certain offices of Inst. 1840" (Offsite-box 77, Folder 2)
    - "Letters - 1840" (Offsite-box 77, Folder 3)
    - "Reports and Papers 1840" (1 of 3) (Offsite-box 77, Folder 4)
    - "Reports and Papers - 1840" (2 of 3) (Offsite-box 77, Folder 5)
    - "Reports and Papers - 1840" (3 of 3) (Offsite-box 77, Folder 6)
    - "Fair Copies of Some of Testimony on Investigation - 1840" (Offsite-box 77, Folder 7)
    - "Vouchers from April 1840 to April 1841", 1839-1841 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 8)
    - "Vouchers T.B. Wakeman Superintendent No. 164-241 April 8, 1841 to April 13, 1842", 1840-1841 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 9)
    - "Reports of the Finance Committee of the American Institute 1840 to 1859", 1840-1859 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 10)
    - "Applications for Membership - 1841", 1839-1841 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 1)
    - "Appropriations made by the American Institute No. 1 to 25, April 8, 1841 to Dec. 13, 1849", 1841-1849 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 2)
    - "Letters, 1841", 1840-1841 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 3)
    - "Reports and Papers 1841", 1840-1841 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 4)
    - "Reports and Papers. Evidence taken before a committee of the American Institute to investigate charges against officers - appointed June 11, 1841", 1839-1840 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 5)
    - "Petty Cash Bills 1841-1842" (Offsite-box 78, Folder 6)
    - "Applications for Membership - 1842" (Offsite-box 78, Folder 7)
    - "Report and Papers - 1842" (Offsite-box 78, Folder 8)
    - "Letters 1842" (Offsite-box 78, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence 1842-1848 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 1)
    - "Vouchers from April 1842 to April 1843", 1841-1843 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 2)
    - "Letters - 1843" (Offsite-box 79, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Reports 1843-1844 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 4)
    - "Memorandums State Appropriation, Albany NY, 1843 to 1889", 1841-1890 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 5)
    - "Reports and Papers 1843" (Offsite-box 79, Folder 6)
    - "Russell Planetarium, Bills Paid, Benefit for the Library of the American Institute", 1843 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 7)
    - "Vouchers April 1843 to April 1844", 1843-1844 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 8)
    - "Applications for Membership - 1844" (1 of 2), 1843-1844 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 9)
    - "Applications for Membership - 1844" (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 79, Folder 10)
    - "Letters 1844, American Institute" (1 of 2), 1844-1845 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 1)
    - "Letters 1844, American Institute" (2 of 2), 1844-1845 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 2)
    - "Letters, Silk Convention - 1844" (Offsite-box 80, Folder 3)
    - "Reports and Papers 1844" (Offsite-box 80, Folder 4)
    - "Reports committee to confer with the NY State Agri. Soc. For a fair in N.Y., Memorandums, Forms, By Laws, Botanic Garden in Florida, St. John's Geological Survey, Mead on Glover's Fruits", 1844, 1848-1856 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 5)
    - "Vouchers from April 1844 to April 1845", 1844-1845 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 6)
    - "Applications for Membership - 1845" (Offsite-box 80, Folder 7)
    - "Letters - 1845" (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 80, Folder 8)
    - "Letters - 1845" (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 81, Folder 1)
    - Reports and Papers, 1845 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 2)
    - Accounts - E.T. Backhouse in Account with the State of New York, 1845-1854 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 3)
    - "Petty Cash Bills 1845 to 1869" (1 of 3), 1845-1855 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 4)
    - "Petty Cash Bills 1845 to 1869" (2 of 3), 1856-1866 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 5)
    - "Petty Cash Bills 1845 to 1869" (3 of 3), 1866-1869 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 6)
    - "Report of the Trustees of the American Institute - 1845", 1846 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 7)
    - "Vouchers from April 1845 to April 1846 / Bills Paid 1845 '46", 1845-1846 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 8)
    - "Applications for Membership 1846" (1 of 2), 1844-1846 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 9)
    - "Applications for Membership 1846" (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 82, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - 1846 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 2)
    - "Letters and Statements for Annual Report, 1846-1848 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 3)
    - "Papers in Annual Report - 1846" (Offsite-box 82, Folder 4)
    - "Reports and Papers 1846" (Offsite-box 82, Folder 5)
    - "Vouchers for April 1846 to April 1847", 1846-1847 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 6)
    - "Applications for Membership 1847" (1 of 2), 1845 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 7)
    - "Applications for Membership 1847" (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 82, Folder 8)
    - "Charters, By Laws, Reports", 1847-1848 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Reports - 1847-1848 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1847-1849 (Offsite-box 83, Folder 1)
    - "Reports and Papers - 1847" (Offsite-box 83, Folder 2)
    - "Report on Miscellaneous - 1847 - J.W.C." (Offsite-box 83, Folder 3)
    - "Vouchers from April 1847 to April 1848", 1847-1848 (Offsite-box 83, Folder 4)
    - "Applications for Membership of the American Institute - 1848", 1847-1848 (Offsite-box 83, Folder 5)
    - "Papers in Annual Report 1848" (Offsite-box 83, Folder 6)
    - "Reports and Papers 1848", 1847-1848 (Offsite-box 83, Folder 7)
    - "Vouchers from April 1848 to April 1849", 1848-1850 (Offsite-box 83, Folder 8)
    - "Applications for Membership of the American Institute 1849" (1 of 2), 1848-1849 (Offsite-box 83, Folder 9)
    - "Applications for Membership of the American Institute 1849" (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 83, Folder 10)
    - "Letters 1849" (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 84, Folder 1)
    - "Letters 1849" (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 84, Folder 2)
    - "Memorandums -- A. Chandler Sup. and Agent -- 1849", 1849-1850 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 3)
    - "Reports and Papers 1849", 1849-1850 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 4)
    - "Reports, Finance Committee Jan. 29, 1849; Jun. 14 1849; July 31, 1851; Oct. 31, 1851; Jan. 30, 1852", 1849, 1851, 1852 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 5)
    - Bills and Accounts, 1849-1851 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 6)
    - "Vouchers from April 1849 to April 1850", 1849-1850 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 7)
    - "1849 Amusing Bits" (Offsite-box 84, Folder 8)
    - "Expired Leases, American Institute 1849-1880", 1849, 1855-1882 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 9)
    - "Applications for Membership of the American Institute - 1850", 1849-1850 (Offsite-box 84, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - 1850 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 1)
    - "Reports and Papers, 1850" (Offsite-box 85, Folder 2)
    - "Lecture Bills 1850, Paid by John W. Chambers" (Offsite-box 85, Folder 3)
    - "Vouchers from April 1850 - April 1851" (Offsite-box 85, Folder 4)
    - "Receipts from E.T. Backhouse, Treasurer, Collections, from Nov. 1, 1850 to January 29, 1859", 1850-1859 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 5)
    - "Appropriation No. 26, $2,346.70, April 11, 1850, Finance Committee to Treasurer, etc.", 1850-1858 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 6)
    - "Applications for Membership of the American Institute, 1851" (Offsite-box 85, Folder 7)
    - "Reports and Papers, 1851" (Offsite-box 85, Folder 8)
    - "Vouchers from Apr. 1851 - April 1852", 1851-1852 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 9)
    - "Treasurer's Authority to Pay Bills, 1851-1879" (1 of 2), 1851-1868 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 10)